One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Enter: Tony Tony Chopper
Tony Tony Chopper
Aren't you...
Ters taraftan...
peeking the wrong way?
dikizlemiyor musun?
It's too late now... and you're still clearly visible.
Artık çok geç... Üstelik hâlâ görünüyorsun!
Just what are you?
Sen nesin böyle?
Sh-Shut up, human!
K-Kapa' çeneni, insan!
Also, how's your fever?
Ayrıca, ateşin nasıl?
It talked!
Konuştu!
Be quiet, Chopper!
Sessiz ol, Chopper!
Your fever seems to have come down a little, girl.
Ateşin bir tık düşmüş gibi duruyor, kızım.
Are ya happy?
Mutlu musun?
Who are you?
Sen de kimsin?
Hmm, 38.2 degrees... Not too shabby.
Hmm,  38.2°... Fena sayılmaz.
I'm a doctor. Dr. Kureha. Call me Doctorine.
Ben doktorum. Dr. Kureha. Bana Doktorine diyebilirsin.
Doctor... Then I'm in the...
Doktor... O zaman ben...
The secret to my youth?
Gençliğimin sırrı mı?
No, I didn't ask that.
Hayır, onu sormadım.
You're right. You're in the castle on top of the mountain.
Evet. Dağın tepesindeki kaledesin.
Then there were two others with me, right?
Yanımda iki kişi daha vardı, değil mi?
Yeah, they're sound asleep in the next room.
Evet, yan odada mışıl mışıl uyuyorlar.
What tough guys...
Amma dayanıklılar...
Look here.
Bak.
This was the cause.
Sebebi buydu.
What... is this?
Bu... ne?
You were bitten by a kestia.
Bir kestia tarafından ısırılmışsın.
It's a poisonous tick that's only found in hot and humid jungles.
Sıcak ve nemli ormanlarda bulunan çok zehirli bir kene türüdür.
Once you're bitten by it, bacteria enter your body
Isırıldıktan sonra bakteriler vücuduna yayılır,
and incubate for five days, all while causing you pain.
beş gün süren sancılı bir sürece girersin.
Fevers run above 40 degrees with coinfection, myocarditis, arteritis, and cerebritis.
40 derece altı olmayan ateşe, beyin, kalp kası ve atardamar iltihabına yol açar.
Judging by the spread of infection, I'd say you were bitten three days ago.
Enfeksiyonun yayılımına bakarsak, üç gün önce ısırılmışsın diyebilirim.
You must have suffered through immense pain.
Dayanılmaz bir acı çekmiş olmalısın.
But, even without treatment, it'd have ended after two more days.
Ama tedavi görmeseydin bile acısı iki güne biterdi.
After two more days...?
2 güne biter miydi?
Yeah. After two more days, you would have died.
Evet, iki güne ölmüş olacaktın.
What?!
Ne?!
It's called the "five-day disease."
Buna "beş gün hastalığı" denir.
I had heard that kestias died out a century ago,
Kestia türünün 100 yıl önce yok olduğunu duymuştum.
so it's good that I kept the antibiotic just in case.
Yine de antibiyotiği elimde tutmam iyi olmuş.
Where did you guys come from?
Siz çocuklar nereden geliyorsunuz?
Were you walking around on a prehistoric jungle island with your belly exposed?
Karnın açık halde tarih öncesi bir orman adasında mı geziniyordun?
But that's just silly...
Gerçi bu çok saçma.
Ah...
Ah...
That ring a bell?
Bir çağrışım yaptı mı?
What a crazy girl...
Ne deli bir kız...
Now...
Şimdi...
Stay in bed. Your treatment hasn't finished yet.
Yatakta kalmaya devam et. Tedavin henüz tamamlanmadı.
Thanks for your help. But my fever is much better already.
Yardımların için çok teşekkürler. Ama ateşim şu an daha iyi.
I can heal on my own now, right?
Kendi başıma parlayamaz mıyım?
You're too optimistic.
Fazla iyimsersin.
This disease normally takes a minimum of ten days to fully treat.
Tam iyileşme için bu hastalık en az on gün tedavi gerektirir.
Unless, of course, you want it to flare up again and kill you this time.
Elbette, hastalığının nüks edip bu sefer seni öldürmesini istiyorsan başka.
Even with my medicine, you'll have to rest at least three days.
Aldığın ilaçla bile en az üç gün dinlenmen lazım.
What...?
Ne...?
I can't stay here for three days!
Burada üç gün kalamam!
Vivi must reach Alabasta soon!
Vivi çabucak Alabasta'ya varmalı!
A patient only leaves my care one of two ways:
Hasta benden sadece iki yolla ayrılabilir:
cured or dead.
Ya iyileşir ya da ölür.
You're not leaving here.
Buradan ayrılmayacaksın.
He climbed this mountain with his bare hands?!
Dağı çıplak elleriyle mi tırmandı?!
This 5,000-meter-high Drum Rock?!
Bu 5.000 metre yüksekliğindeki Drum Kayası'nı mı?!
Nearly his entire body is frostbitten.
Neredeyse tüm vücudu soğuk ısırığı olmuş.
What was he thinking dressing like this?
Bu şekilde giyinerek ne bekliyordu ki?
Throw him in a warm bath immediately.
Onu hemen sıcak bir duşa sok.
This guy's bleeding badly. Six broken ribs and a spinal fissure.
Bu adamda da ciddi kanama var. 6 kırık kaburga ve omurga çatlağı var.
Can I operate on him?
Onu ameliyat edeyim mi?
This girl's the most critical. She's barely alive.
Bu kız birinci önceliğimiz. Neredeyse ölü.
Chopper, ready some phenicol, cardiotonic, and tialcillin.
Chopper, fenikol, kardiyotonik ve thiocilline getir.
Does she have an infection?
Enfeksiyonu mu var?
Yeah, and the pathogen isn't from this island.
Evet, patojenik bulgular bu adada olmadığını gösteriyor.
Don't worry. I'll make both that bleeding kid and this girl all better.
Endişelenme. Kanaması olan çocukla, kızı iyileştireceğim.
You can relax.
Rahatlayabilirsin.
Th-They're my f-friends...!
O-Ollar benim a-arkıdışlarım...!
I get the picture. I'll help them.
Anladım. Onlara yardım edeceğim.
Chopper! Let's begin treatment!
Chopper! Tedaviye başlayalım!
Th-They're my f-friends...!
O-Ollar benim a-arkıdışlarım...!
I'm...
Çok...
I'm hungry...
Çok acıktım...
Meat...
Et...
Venison stew needs to be cooked in a pot for three hours,
Geyik etli güveç, üç saat boyunca tencerede pişirilmeli,
then the meat becomes properly tender.
böylece et iyice yumuşar.
Venison...!
Geyik eti...!
Ahhhh! Help!
Ahhhh! Yardım edin!
Wait, meat!
Bekle, et!
Wait, Luffy! I'll cook him for you!
Bekle, Luffy! Onu senin için pişireceğim!
Nami?!
Nami?!
Nami!
Nami-san!
You got better?
Daha iyi misin?
Yeah, thanks.
Evet, teşekkürler.
Okay, then! I'll make a nutritious venison dish for Nami!
Öyleyse! Nami-san'a sağlıklı bir geyik yemeği hazırlayacağım!
– Wait!
– Bekle!
I'm surprised they can already move around.
Daha şimdiden hareket etmelerine şaşırdım.
What's that talking stuffed deer with the blue nose?
O mavi burunlu konuşan geyik de neyin nesi?
You're asking me what he is?
Bana mı soruyorsun?
Don't run away, meat!
Kaçma, et!
Wait, Luffy! I'm telling you not to eat it yet!
Bekle, Luffy! Onu henüz yiyemezsin diyorum!
Stop it, humans!
Durun artık, insanlar!
His name is Chopper. He's just a reindeer with a blue nose.
Onun adı Chopper. O sadece mavi burunlu bir ren geyiği.
Reindeer don't talk.
Ren geyikleri konuşamaz ki.
S-Stop it, you jerks!
Y-Yapmayın, salaklar!
S-Stop it!
D-Durun!
He's a regular reindeer that just happened to...
Kendisi normal bir ren geyiği, ama biraz farklı...
Just happened to...?
Nasıl farklı...?
I'm not food!
Ben yemek değilim!
...eat the Human-Human Fruit.
İnsan-İnsan Meyvesi yediği için farklı.
The Human-Human Fruit...
İnsan-İnsan Meyvesi...
One of the devil fruits...
Bir şeytan meyvesi...
Yeah. He's become a reindeer with human abilities.
Doğru. İnsan yetenekleri olan bir ren geyiği haline geldi.
Rats! Rats!
Hay aksi! Hay aksi!
And I taught him everything I know about medicine.
Tüm tıbbi bilgilerimi ona öğrettim.
Oh, it's already over?
Ne, şimdiden bitti mi?
What a disappointing bunch.
Ne büyük hayal kırıklığı.
– What was that?! – Amazing...
– O neydi öyle?! – Müthiş...
Amazing...
İnanılmaz...
All right! Good job, Zoro! Just as I instructed!
Tamamdır! Aferin Zoro! Talimatlarımı yerine getirdin!
Let's find Dalton!
Hadi Dalton-san'ı bulalım!
Yeah!
Evet!
Thank you!
Teşekkür ederiz!
Hurry up! Dig everywhere!
Çabuk! Her yeri kazın!
So, what's all this fuss about?
Peki, bu saçmalık da neydi?
I'll explain later! Let's help them!
Sonra açıklarım! Hadi onlara yardım edelim!
Dalton! Please be alive!
Dalton-san! Lütfen hayatta olun!
Join my crew! Please, old lady!
Tayfama katıl! Lütfen, ihtiyar teyze!
We need a doctor on our ship!
Gemimize bir doktor gerekiyor!
Luffy! You said that's your name, right?
Luffy! İsmin buydu, değil mi?
Yeah, I did, old la–
Evet, ihtiyar tey–
Watch... what you say!
Ağzından çıkanı kulağın duysun!
I'm still in my youthful 130s.
Gençliğimin baharında 130'umdayım.
Whoa. What an incredible old hag.
Vay be, ne tuhaf bir kocakarı.
Are you asking me to be a pirate?
Korsan olmamı mı istiyorsun?
Don't be ridiculous! It'd be a waste of my glorious time.
Saçmalama! Değerli zamanıma yazık olur.
I'm not interested in the sea.
Denizler ilgimi çekmiyor.
Who cares? Let's go on an adventure, old lady!
Kimin umurunda? Hadi maceraya atılalım, ihtiyar teyze!
Hey now. I just told you to watch what you say, didn't I?
Hey, ne dedim ben sana? Ağızını topla demedim mi?
So they're pirates...
Yani onlar korsan...
Wait, meat!
Bekle, et!
Wait!
Bekle!
Hold it, you brats!
Durun, sizi veletler!
Hold on, Nami! I'll cook a nutritious reindeer dish!
Dayan, Nami-san! Senin için besleyici bir ren geyiği pişireceğim!
Before that, I'll eat you guys!
Ondan önce, ben sizi yiyeceğim!
– The old hag!
– Kocakarı!
Where the heck did she come from?!
Bu da nereden çıktı şimdi?!
She's coming!
Geliyor!
She's coming! She's coming!
Geliyor! Geliyor!
Forget the food. I just want some peace and quiet.
Yemeği boş verin. Biraz sessizlik ve huzur istiyorum sadece.
Snow? Even though we're inside the castle...?
Kar mı? Kalenin içinde bile mi?
So cold...!
Soğuk!
I'll close the door.
Kapıyı kapatsam iyi olur.
Hey! Stay in bed!
Hey! Yatakta kal!
You still have a fever!
Hâlâ ateşin var!
I don't. It seems like it's pretty much gone.
Sanmıyorum. Neredeyse tamamen geçti gibi.
Looks like I lost them...
Kurtuldum sanırım…
Even so, no!
Yine de, hayır!
Doctorine's medicine makes the fever go away quickly.
Doktorine'nin ilaçları çok etkilidir.
But the kestia's bacteria still remain in your body.
Ama kestia bakterisi hâlâ vücudunda.
You need to have your antibiotic shot and stay in bed.
Antibiyotiklerini almalı ve dinlenmelisin.
Thank you.
Teşekkürler.
You've been taking care of me, right?
Benimle sen ilgilendin, değil mi?
Sh...
Ka...
Shut up!
Kapa' çeneni!
I don't wanna be thanked by a human!
İnsanların teşekkürlerini istemiyorum!
Don't mock me! You jerk!
Dalga geçme benimle! Seni ahmak~!
Don't be silly, you dummy!
Salak olma, sersem~!
Seriously, don't be so...
Cidden, çok da şey...
He's quite the open book, isn't he?
İçi dışı bir olanlardan, ha?
This castle is strange. It's cold and there's snow inside.
Ne tuhaf bi' kale. İçerisi soğuk ve karla dolu.
Oh...?
Oh...?
Ahhh! It's cold!
Ahhh! Çok soğuk!
You keep taking your sweet time with that!
Dedim ya, kafan biraz yavaş çalışıyor!
Look at this.
Şuna bak.
There's snow everywhere in the castle.
Kalenin her yerinde kar var.
The doors for the unused rooms are all frozen, too.
Kullanılmayan odaların hepsi donmuş.
Hold it! Hold it! Hold it!
Bekle! Bekle! Bekle!
Wh-Wh-Whoa! Hey, Luffy! Stop asking that old bag to join us!
H-H-Hey! Hey, Luffy! Şu kocakarıyı tayfaya almayı unut gitsin!
She's not a doctor, she's a murderer!
O doktor falan değil, o bir katil!
Are you guys pirates?
Sizler korsan mısınız?
Yes...
Evet...
R-Real ones?
G-Gerçek mi?
Real ones.
Evet gerçek korsan.
You have a flag with a skull?
Bayrağınızda kuru kafa var mı?
It's attached to our ship. Are you interested in pirates?
Gemimizde asılı. Korsanlara ilgi mi duyuyorsun?
No! You idiot! No!
Hayır! Salak! Hayır!
You idiot!
Seni aptal!
Okay. Okay. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Tamam. Özür dilerim. Pardon.
But... then...
Peki bizimle gelmek...
wanna come too?
ister misin?
What?!
Ne?!
To the sea! Why don't you come with us?
Denize açılalım! Neden bize katılmıyorsun?
Hm?
Hm?
If you do, it'll really help me out!
Gelirsen, bana çok yardımı olur.
With a doctor, I won't have to stay here for three days, right?
Gemide doktor olursa, üç gün burada kalmam gerekmez, değil mi?
On top of that, on our ship, we–
Üstelik gemimizde biz–
D-Don't be ridiculous!
S-Saçmalama!
I'm a reindeer!
Ben bir ren geyiğiyim!
There's no way I can stay with humans!
İnsanlarla yaşamamın imkânı yok!
To start with, don't you get scared when you see me?
Şöyle bir baktığında, benden korkmuyor musun?
I'm a reindeer, but I stand on two legs and I even speak.
Ben bir ren geyiğiyim ama iki ayak üstünde duruyor ve konuşuyorum.
What? Are you trying to scare me?
Ne? Beni korkutmaya mı çalışıyorsun?
My nose is blue, too...
Ayrıca burnum da mavi...
There you are!
İşte buradasın!
Reindeer!
Ren geyiği!
– Wait!
– Dur!
Those brats sure are quick.
Çok hızlı veletler.
I don't like it, girl.
Senin yaptığını da beğenmedim.
What?
Ne?
Who gave you permission to tempt the reindeer behind my back?
Benden habersiz ren geyiğimi ayartmaya mı çalışıyorsun?
Oh? Do I need permission to make a move on a man?
Ne? Bir erkeğe yanaşmak için izin mi almam lazım?
No, you don't. If you wanna take him, go right ahead.
Hayır, değil. Eğer onu istiyorsan, önden buyur.
But it won't be easy.
Ama kolay olmayacaktır.
He has a scar in his heart— a big scar that even I can't cure.
Kalbinde öyle büyük bir yara var ki, ben bile iyileştiremiyorum.
The moment he came into this world, his herd and his parents abandoned him.
Bu dünyaya geldiğinde, sürüsü ve ailesi onu terk etti.
What?
Ne?
It was all because of his blue nose.
Tek sebebi burnunun mavi olmasıydı.
He always walked at the very back of the herd all by himself
Kendisi her zaman sürünün en arkasında yürürdü.
even though he was just a newborn child.
Hem de bir yeni doğan olmasına rağmen.
After he ate a devil fruit, he was treated like a true monster.
Şeytan meyvesi yedikten sonra tamamen canavar muamelesi gördü.
The other reindeer drove him out of the herd.
Diğer ren geyikleri onu sürüden tamamen dışladı.
There was no way he could ever go back to being an ordinary reindeer.
Artık sıradan bir ren geyiği olarak sürüye dönmesinin bir yolu yoktu.
Still, he wanted friends...
Yine de, arkadaş edinmek istedi...
So he went down to a village, this time as a human.
O yüzden bir köye gitti, bu sefer bir insan olarak.
Hey! What's that creature?
Hey! O yaratık da neyin nesi?!
But his figure wasn't exactly human, either.
Ama görünüşü tam bir insan gibi de değildi.
For some reason, his nose also remained blue.
Bir sebepten ötürü, burnu insan formunda da mavi kaldı.
It must be a yeti!
Bu bir yeti olmalı!
It's dangerous! Get the children inside quickly!
Çok tehlikeli! Çabuk çocukları içeri alın!
A gun! Bring me a gun!
Silah! Bana bir silah verin!
Shoot it dead!
Öldürün onu!
You damn monster!
Seni pis yaratık!
Go away!
Uzaklaş!
He didn't know what was wrong,
Neyi yanlış yaptığını bilmiyordu...
nor did he know what to blame.
veya kimi suçlayacağını.
You damn monster!
Seni lanet canavar!
All he wanted were friends, but he was called a monster...
Tek istediği arkadaş edinmekti ama ona canavar dediler.
He was no longer a reindeer.
Artık bir ren geyiği değildi.
He wasn't a human, either.
Bir insan da değildi.
And so, he had to live alone.
Bu yüzden, yalnız yaşamak zorunda kaldı.
Can you guys heal the scar in his heart?
Sizler, onun kalbindeki yarayı iyileştirebilir misiniz?
Hey, Luffy. Look at that door at the front entrance. It's wide open.
Hey, Luffy. Şu girişteki kapıya bak. Sonuna kadar açık.
No wonder it's cold.
Bu yüzden soğuk.
In any case, let's close this door.
Yine de kapıyı kapatalım.
Otherwise, we might as well be out in the snow.
Yoksa ha içerideyiz ha dışarıda.
Hey! Stop it! Don't touch that door!
Hey! Durun! Sakın o kapıya dokunmayın!
Never mind him. Let's close it, or we'll freeze to death.
Boş ver onu. Kapatalım yoksa burada donarak öleceğiz.
Definitely.
Kesinlikle.
Hey! Didn't I tell you to...
Hey! Size sakın o kapıya dokunmayın...
stop it?!
demedim mi?!
What's with him? Why is he angry?
Onun nesi var? Neden sinirlendi?
Hey, Luffy. Come over here.
Hey, Luffy. Buraya gel.
Look up there.
Yukarıya bak.
They're snowbird hatchlings. So, if we close the door, they'll fall.
Bebek kar kuşları. Kapı kapanırsa, düşecekler.
That's why they can't close it.
Demek bu yüzden açık duruyor.
– It's cold!
– Çok soğuk!
Hold on a sec.
Bekle bir saniye.
What is it?
Ne oldu?
Ah!
Ah!
Didn't he talk just now?!
Az önce konuşuyor muydu o?
And come to think of it, he was standing on two legs.
Şimdi fark ettim de ayrıca iki ayağının üstündeydi.
– He's a monster!
– O bir canavar!
Wh-What the heck is that?
O-O nasıl bir şey öyle?
He's walking on two legs...
İki ayağının üzerinde yürüyor...
He's a reindeer...
Ren geyiği...
He's fluffy...
Tüylü...
He's short...
Kısa boylu...
He becomes big...
Kocaman olabiliyor...
– And he's a monster!
– Ve canavara dönüşüyor!
What a cool guy! I like him!
Ne kadar havalı! Ona bayıldım!
Sanji! Let's have him join us!
Sanji! Hadi onu tayfaya alalım!